+44 7565 506 022 · jamesdrysdale84@gmail.com · linkedin.com/in/james-drysdale · github.com/JamesDrysdale

Front-end developer with proven leadership experience, and ability to mentor and develop others. Passionate about building accessible, sustainable products that delight users with a great user experience. With over 3 years of experience in demanding technical roles, now looking to grow further in a company with a shared commitment to excellence.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

CodeClan, Edinburgh

2022 - 2023

Instructor for software development and UX

- Taught over 100 students Software Development using Python, JavaScript, Java and related frameworks. Database Development, programming concepts such as Object Oriented programming, and Agile methodologies.
- Coordinated 3 new Youth Academies in Perth and Tweedbank, which created a pipeline for young people with no coding knowledge or experience to upskill, going on to further education, apprenticeships or internships after graduation.
- Wrote and delivered a short course on UX Fundamentals upskilling more than a dozen learners.
- Facilitated an employee network group for LGBTQ+ staff, which promoted DEI.

Daxtra Technologies, Musselburgh

2022 - 2022

Lead Technical Support Engineer

- Liased with senior management, fostering positive communication and a strong supportive culture at every level of the company, increasing staff retention by 30%.
- Inspirational leadership and guidance helped colleagues resolve issues more quickly, increasing client satisfaction by 12%.
- Facilitated weekly team meetings and tirelessly removed any blockers colleagues were facing, consequently, team members resolved 4% more issues.

Daxtra Technologies, Musselburgh

2021 - 2022

Technical Support Engineer

- Delivered 1st and 2nd line technical support, delivering excellent customer service to external clients
- Debugged over 2000 issues with technologies such as Linux, Apache, PERL, Node.js, SQL, MongoDB and XML to resolve application and server issues within SLAs.
- Exceeded KPI targets while also making time to assist and mentor junior colleagues. As a result, the whole team's performance improved by 24% over time.

You Understood, Remote

2020 - 2021

UX and UI Designer

- Incorporated UX design principles, the Laws of UX, and UI Design Patterns when designing over 2 dozen screens for the mobile app, and web app, to ensure accessibility and ease of use.
- Created and presented wireframes and prototypes of designs to stakeholders using Figma, then incorporated feedback to make the product better iteratively.
- Followed agile methodologies and collaborated with the development team during weekly sprint planning sessions, and sprint reviews to drive the project forward.

Paths For All, Remote

2020 - 2020

- Designed and developed a feature using React Native with styled-components to guide users through balance-building exercises, allowing users to control the number of reps and record results.
- Adhered to agile methodologies with weekly sprints, daily stand-ups, and using a Trello Kanban board.

EDUCATION

CodeClan, Edinburgh

2020

Professional Software Development - Professional Development Award (SCQF Level 8)

SKILLS

- Front-end: HTML, CSS, Tailwind, Bootstrap, Javascript, React, Next.js
- Back-end: Node.js, SQL, Postgres, Express, MongoDB
- **UX and Design**: Figma, Lighthouse
- **Other**: Git, GitHub, Asana, Scrum, Agile Methodologies, WordPress and other content management systems.

VOLUNTEERING

ADPList Mentoring Platform, Remote

2020 - Present

Mentoring

- Provide mentorship and career guidance for Software Development and UX students/graduates/career changers and junior professionals.
- Awarded twice by ADPList mentoring platform in recognition of being a top 1% mentor.

Scottish Tech Army, Remote

2020 - 2023

Software Developer

• Completed User Acceptance Testing for the SOLE platform, which helped dozens of businesses/charities in Dunbar provide services online during the COVID-19 pandemic.